Finding Aid for Ecology Center of Ann Arbor records, 1969-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ecology Center of Ann Arbor records
1969-2010
Ecology Center of Ann Arbor.
88272 Bw 2; Bw Outsize
Founded in 1970, the Ecology Center of Ann Arbor is a grassroots community organization committed to increasing environmental awareness. Records include meeting minutes, financial statements, correspondence, news clippings, photographs and publications relating to the activities and functions of the organization, especially in the areas of recycling, energy conservation, and ecology.
31.5 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the Ecology Center of Ann Arbor (donor no. 7198 ) in several accessions beginning in February 1985.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Ecology Center of Ann Arbor was formed one month after Earth Day in May 1970. ENACT (Environmental Action for Survival) and a group of community volunteers founded the Ecology Center as an independent, non-profit organization for the promotion of environmental awareness, education, and advocacy. The organization's initial commitment to the environment was reflected in its recycling program, environmental film festival, radio program and recycled Christmas card sales in 1970.
In 1971, the Ecology Center opened a recycling station at 2050 South Industrial Road in Ann Arbor. In 1982, the Ecology Center merged with Recycle Ann Arbor to provide curbside collection of recyclable paper, glass, cans, oil, and aluminum.
The Ecology Center offers many services in addition to recycling. It strives to increase local awareness of environmental problems through involvement in educational and service programs in homes, in the Ann Arbor Schools, and in community projects. One example is a home energy conservation team that inspects and recommends retrofitting to enhance a home's energy efficiency. The organization also has a hotline that provides information on environmental issues.
Outreach programs such as recycling education and home heat conservation workshops are supported by the Ecology Center's library. In cooperation with the Ann Arbor Public Library, the Ecology Center maintains this community environmental resource center. The center has also been involved in organizing annual Earth Day activities, especially in 1990, the twentieth anniversary of that event.
The Ecology Center is also active in environmental lobbying. For example, in the mid 1970s, the Ecology Center campaigned for a state referendum on returnable bottles. The Center advises on a number of land use plans to prevent urban sprawl in Ann Arbor, as well as policies to control air and water quality, and toxic waste. The center also played an instrumental role in the Right-To-Know and Right-To-Act campaigns of the late 1980s and early 1990s.
The Ecology Center of Ann Arbor is funded by membership fees, business donations, grants, and fundraising events. Two long-standing fundraising events are the annual sale of Christmas cards and the Bike-A-Thon.
A number of different independent organizations, such as Ann Arbor Tomorrow, Citizens' Association for Area Planning, and Project Grow, have been fostered by the Ecology Center. The organization also has a strong affiliation with the Washtenaw Environmental Council.
The records of the Ecology Center document the efforts of this grassroots community organization to increase environmental awareness through the establishment of recycling and energy conservation programs, and by publicizing the need for pesticide control and responsible solid waste disposal among other issues. The series in the record group are: Administrative Files, Topical Files, Printed Materials and Publicity, and Visual Materials.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor Tomorrow Council.; Citizens Association for Area Planning.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Ecology Center of Ann Arbor.; Ecology--Michigan.; Energy conservation--Michigan.; Recycle Ann Arbor.; Recycling (Waste, etc.)--Michigan.; Washtenaw County (Mich.); Washtenaw Environmental Council.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Bicycles and tricycles.; Bike-a-thon (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Recycling--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Videotapes.
- Administrative Files
  The Administrative Files consist of annual reports, board minutes, records of annual meetings, planning files, notebooks from staff meetings, and the Ecology Center Handbook, by-laws, and articles of incorporation.
  - Annual Reports
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - 1975-1979 (Box 1)
    - 1980 (Box 1)
    - 1983 (Box 1)
    - 1984-1986 (Box 1)
    - 1987 (Box 1)
    - 1989-1995 (Box 1)
    - 1996-2006 (Box 1)
      (miscellaneous)
  - Board Minutes and Attachments
    - 1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974 (Box 1)
    - 1975 (Box 1)
    - 1976 (Box 1)
    - 1977 (Box 1)
    - 1978 (Box 1)
    - 1979 (Box 1)
    - 1980 (Box 1)
    - 1981 (Box 1)
    - 1982, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1983 (Box 1)
    - 1984 (Box 1)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - March 1986-November 1987 (Box 1)
    - 1988 (Box 1)
    - 1989 (Box 2)
    - 1990, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 1991 (Box 2)
    - (and monthly reports), scattered dates, 1991-1996 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Committee Meetings, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Annual Meetings, 1981-1999; 9 folders (Box 3)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1970-1971; 1976 (Box 3)
    (includes Certified Resolution of Change of Registered Office)
  - By-laws, 1970; 1982; 1988; 1990 (Box 3)
  - Committees
    - Internal Management and Procedures (IMP), 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Sub-Committee on Interim Structure Unincorporated (SISU), 1987-1988 (Box 3)
    - Newsletter Advisory Committee, 1988; 1990-1991 (Box 3)
    - Outreach and Development, 1988; 1991-1994 (Box 3)
    - Personnel Committee, 1987-1991 (Box 3)
    - Programs and Policy (PPC), 1989-2002; 3 folders (Box 3)
      (includes EPC -- Environmental Policy Committee)
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming, 1987-1989 (Box 3)
    - Outgoing, 1987-1989 (Box 3)
  - Ecology Center Handbook, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Facilities Assessment, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Financial Audits, 1990-1994 (Box 3)
  - Financial Reports
    - 1973-1977 (Box 4)
    - 1984-1989 (Box 4)
  - Floor Plan, 1972 (Box 4)
  - History and Founding of Ecology Center (Box 4)
  - Information Sharing Notebook, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - Internal Organizational Analysis, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Job Descriptions (Box 4)
  - Membership, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Mission Statement and Goals (Box 4)
  - Planning
    - 1982-1988 (Box 4)
    - 1990 (Box 4)
    - 1992 (Box 4)
  - Planning Retreat, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Planning Retreat, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Planning Retreat, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Planning Retreat, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Planning Week
    - 1975 (Box 4)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - 1978 (Box 4)
    - 1981 (Box 4)
    - 1982 (Box 4)
    - 1983 (Box 4)
    - 1984 (Box 4)
    - 1985 (Box 4)
  - Program planning and mission statements (Box 4)
  - Staff Lists (Box 4)
  - Staff Meetings Notebooks
    - 1981 (Box 4)
    - 1982 (Box 4)
    - 1983 (Box 4)
    - 1984 (Box 4)
  - Staff Meetings, 1988-1991; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Staff Orientation, circa 1987 (Box 5)
  - Strategic Plan, 1994-1998 (Box 5)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files are arranged into four chronological subseries, each arranged alphabetically. As there is considerable overlap in the dates of the three subseries, the researcher will need to examine each set of files for information on a given topic.
  - 1970-1990, mainly 1971-1985
    The 1970-1990 subseries contains many files on the Ecology Center's recycling and energy conservation outreach programs, as well as on its fundraising activities. Within these files, there is considerable information about Recycle Ann Arbor, Ecology Week and other educational programs, the Washtenaw Environmental Council and associate organizations, Ann Arbor Tomorrow, and Citizens' Association for Area Planning.
    - Allen Creek Drain Pollution, 1983 (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor City Budget, 1976-1978 (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor Energy Steering Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor Parks Advisory Commission, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor Tomorrow, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor Transportation Authority, 1973-1979 (Box 6)
    - Benefit Concert, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Bibliography of Environmental Literature (Box 6)
    - Bike-A-Thon
      - 1971-1981 (Box 6)
      - 1982-1987 (Box 6)
      - 1990 (Box 6)
    - Bikepath Planning, 1973-1984 (Box 6)
    - Billboard Legislation, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Bottle Deposit Bill, 1971-1974; 1979 (Box 6)
    - Candidate Questionnaires (Box 6)
    - Capital Improvements Budget, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
    - Carole Cristoff Memorial Fund, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Cider Project, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Circulation Study, 1974-1976 (Box 6)
    - Citizens' Association for Area Planning, 1972-1980 (Box 6)
    - Citizens for Alternatives to Chemical Contamination (Box 6)
    - City Planning Tours, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Clean Michigan Bill (Box 6)
    - Cleveland Metal Abrasive Company, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Community Forum on Environmental Legislation, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Community Organic Garden
      - Grant Report, 1972 (Box 6)
      - 1972-1974 (Box 6)
    - Community Service Award, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Council for Rural Awareness (Box 6)
    - Discover Energy Series, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Downtown Planning, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Earth Day, 1980 (Box 6)
    - Earth Week, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - "Ecology and Man" Radio Program (Box 6)
    - Ecology Center Conference, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Ecology Month, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Ecology Week
      - 1982 (Box 6)
      - 1983 (Box 6)
      - 1984 (Box 6)
      - 1985 (Box 6)
    - Economic Development Corporation, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - Education Programs
      - 1982 (Box 6)
      - 1983 (Box 6)
      - Leslie Labs, 1983 (Box 6)
      - 1984 (Box 6)
      - 1985 (Box 6)
      - 1987 (Box 6)
    - Electricity (Box 6)
    - ENACT, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Energy Conservation Program
      - Proposal (Box 6)
      - 1981 (Box 6)
      - 1983 (Box 6)
    - Energy Fair, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Energy Learning Center (Box 7)
    - Energy Savings in Rental Housing Law, Proposal A, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Environmental Education (Box 7)
    - Environmental Film Festival (Box 7)
    - Farmers' Market Commodities Exchange Center, proposal, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - Flint Environmental Action Team (Box 7)
    - Garage Sale, 1979 (Box 7)
    - General Development Plan, Ann Arbor, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Great Lakes Commission (Box 7)
    - Great Lakes Environmental Research Laboratory (Box 7)
    - Great Lakes Water Quality (Box 7)
    - Green and Clean Environmental Days, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Greeting Cards
      - 1970-1979 (Box 7)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Home Heat Conservation Workshop, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Horizons on Display Award, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Household Toxics Workshops, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Human Ecology Action League of Michigan (Box 7)
    - Huron River Committee (Box 7)
    - Interfaith Council for Peace (Box 7)
    - Kimberly Hills Conflict, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Library (Box 7)
    - Litter Survey, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Live Christmas Trees, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Low Cost/No Cost Home Energy Conservation Program (Box 7)
    - Macroanalysis Seminars, 1976 (Box 7)
    - McDonald's Construction Controversy, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Association of Environmental Professionals (Box 7)
    - Michigan Citizen Organizations Acting Together (Box 7)
    - Michigan Environmental Information Access Network Proposal (Box 7)
    - Michigan Lake and Stream Associations (Box 7)
    - Michigan Natural Areas Council (Box 7)
    - Michigan United Conservation Clubs (Box 7)
    - Moore, Dr. John F., consultant (Box 7)
    - North American Recycling conference, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Northern Michigan Environmental Action Council, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Nuclear Power, 1979-1980 (Box 7)
    - Oil Recycling Program, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Organic Farming Film Festival, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Park at Main and Huron, 1973-1978 (Box 7)
    - Pesticides (Box 7)
    - Pilot Project, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Project Grow
      - 1972-1978 (Box 7)
      - 1984-1986 (Box 7)
    - Propane Feasibility Campaign, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Public Awareness Survey, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Public Interest Research Group in Michigan (Box 7)
    - Quote Book, 1978-1980 (Box 7)
    - Rare Bike Roundup, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Recombinant DNA, 1976-1978 (Box 7)
    - Recycle Ann Arbor
      - Merger (Box 7)
      - General Membership Meeting Minutes, July 1980-July 1982 (Box 7)
      - Board Notebook, August 1981-June 1982 (Box 7)
      - General, 1982 (Box 7)
      - General, 1983 (Box 7)
      - Budget and Evaluation, 1984 (Box 8)
      - Staff Meeting Minutes
        - 1984 (Box 8)
        - 1985 (Box 8)
      - Open House, 1986 (Box 8)
      - Tenth Birthday, 1988 (Box 8)
      - General, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Recycle Week
      - 1981 (Box 8)
      - 1982 (Box 8)
      - 1983 (Box 8)
      - 1984 (Box 8)
    - Recycling
      - Ann Arbor, 1977-1980 (Box 8)
      - Curbside Pickup, 1971-1974; 1981-1983 (Box 8)
      - Glass, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
      - St. Joseph's Hospital, 1972 (Box 8)
      - University of Michigan, 1970-1980 (Box 8)
    - Recycling Station, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Returnables, 1973-1979 (Box 8)
    - Reunion, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Right to Know, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
    - Rites o' Spring, 1972-1976 (Box 8)
    - Road Construction
      - General, 1978 (Box 8)
      - Eisenhower Parkway, 1973 (Box 8)
      - Fuller/Glen Road, 1980 (Box 8)
      - Packard/Beakes Bypass (Box 8)
      - Platt/I-94 Interchange, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Road Salt Policy, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Schechtman Appointment, 1971 (Box 8)
    - School of Public Health Phone Survey, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Seasonal Lifestyle Tips, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Seminars, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - Sewage Treatment, 1974-1977 (Box 8)
    - Sewer Construction Ban, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Shop Ann Arbor Days, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Solar Energy Workshop, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Solid Waste, 1978-1982 (Box 8)
    - Storytimes, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Strip Mining, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Sun Day, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Tag Day
      - 1978-1979 (Box 8)
      - 1982 (Box 8)
      - 1983 (Box 8)
      - 1985 (Box 8)
    - Teach-in on the Environment
      - Ann Arbor, 1970-1972 (Box 8)
      - National, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - Teltran, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Term Papers on the Ecology Center (Box 8)
    - Tip of the Mitt Watershed Council, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Transportation Planning, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Traver Creek Storm Drain, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Tree Planting, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Trout Unlimited, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Tyler Award, 1976 (Box 8)
    - University of Michigan Incinerator, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Upper Peninsula Environmental Coalition, 1985-1987 (Box 8)
    - Urban Stormwater Runoff Control, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Vasectomy Drive, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Walk-a-Thon, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
    - Walker's Guide to Washtenaw County, 1976; 1979 (Box 8)
    - Washtenaw Environmental Council
      - Correspondence and Administrative Papers (Box 8)
      - Meeting Minutes, 1971-1974 (Box 8)
    - Waste Systems Institute of Michigan, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Water Quality, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Wind Generator (Box 8)
    - The Women's Farm and Garden Club, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Zoning, 1975 (Box 8)
  - 1969-1996, mainly 1985-1993
    The 1969-1996 subseries is especially strong on the Bike-A-Thon program, Earth Day celebration, the GEE-WOW (Groundwater Education on Wheels) program, as well as Recycle Ann Arbor.
    - Activities, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Ann Arbor Environmental Interpretive Center (pre-cursor to Ecology Center), 1969 (Box 9)
    - Anniversary Reunions, 1985; 1990; 1995 (Box 9)
    - Bike-A-Thon
      - Clippings (Box 9)
      - Pamphlets (Box 9)
      - Planning, 1986 (Box 9)
      - Posters (Folder Bw)
      - Publicity, 1983; 1985-1986 (Box 9)
    - C.L.E.A.N. (Coalition for Learning Environmental Awareness Now)
      - Environmental Report Card for Ann Arbor Public Schools, 1990 (Box 9)
      - Minutes and Memorandums, 1989-1992 (Box 9)
    - Disposable Plastics Project, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Earth Day, 1990
      - Clippings (Box 9)
      - "Groundswell '90" (Teach-in on the Environment) (Box 9)
      - Outreach (Box 9)
      - Planning (Box 9)
      - University of Michigan Activities (Box 9)
    - Earth Day, 1991-1995 (Box 9)
    - Environmental Education, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Environmental Health, 1994-1996 (Box 9)
    - Footloose in Washtenaw (Walker's Guide) Promotion (Box 9)
    - GEE-WOW (Groundwater Education on Wheels)
      - Newsletter, 1990 (Box 9)
      - Planning and Proposals, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
      - Printed Material and Publicity, 1994-1996 (Box 9)
      - Related Grant Projects, 1988-1992 (Box 9)
      - Washtenaw County G.E.M. (Groundwater Education in Michigan), 1988-1991 (Box 9)
    - Great Lakes Hazardous Household Waste Disposal Conference, 1985
      - Conference Packet (Box 9)
      - Conference Planning (Box 9)
    - Green Elephant Sale, 1972 (Box 9)
    - Greeting Cards (Box 9)
    - Home Energy Works
      - Community Development Program Contract, 1983 (Box 9)
      - Presentation (Box 9)
      - Program Evaluation, 1983 (Box 9)
    - "Living Environmentally" (Adult Education Course), 1990 (Box 9)
    - Legislative Testimony, 1972-1992 (Box 9)
    - Multi-Family Housing Recycling, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Newsletter (Discussions on changing the function and nature of the newsletter), 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Neighbors Against Guns (NAGS), circa 1987 (Box 9)
    - Non-Profit Energy Works
      - Information Packet, 1988 (Box 9)
      - Proposal to the Community Foundation of South-Eastern Michigan, 1988 (Box 9)
      - Quarterly Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 9)
    - Organic Garden
      - Planning (Box 9)
    - Pesticide Task Force Fact Sheets, 1986-1991 (Box 9)
    - Pierce, John, Art Exhibit, 1972 (Box 9)
    - "Recyclables" (Cartoon Advertising Campaign) (Box 9)
    - Recycle Ann Arbor
      - Administrative, 1989-1991 (Box 9)
      - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1989-1991 (Box 9)
      - Contracts, 1990-1991; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Futuring and Reorganization, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
      - Management Agreement and By-Laws, 1990 (Box 10)
      - Pamphlets and Mailings (Box 10)
      - Proposals, 1991 (Box 10)
      - Recycling and Education Center, 1991-1992 (Box 10)
    - Right-To-Act Campaign
      - Administrative, 1992-1993 (Box 10)
      - Information and Outreach, 1992-1993; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Second Refrigerator Bounty Program
      - Final Report, 1989 (Box 10)
      - Photographs and Flyers, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Solar Energy Homes Tour, 1986 (Box 10)
    - Solid Waste Privatization Research, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Toxic Consumer Products and Indoor Air Quality Conference, 1987 (Box 10)
    - University of Michigan Environmental Review Committee (Box 10)
    - Walk-A-Thon, Site Descriptions, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Washtenaw Environmental Council, 1970-1973 (Box 10)
  - 1985-2004, mainly 1990-2000
    The 1985-2004 subseries, among other topics, documents the problem of pesticide control and solid waste disposal, as well as the activities of the Environmental Fund for Michigan and its successor Earth Share of Michigan.
    - Agriculture, Dept. of, Regulation 637 (pesticide use), 1988-1995 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Area Candidates' Forum on the Environment, 1988-1992 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Area Environmental Summit, 2000-2001 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Commercial Recycling Task Force, 1992-1996 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Earth Commission, 1999-2003 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Environmental Agenda, 1989-1994 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Housing Commission, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Landfill, 1987-1994; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Landfill Clean-up, 2001-2003 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Material Recovery Facility, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Natural Features Preservation Ordinance, 1991-1994 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Parks Public Process, 1998 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Planning Commission
      - Audubon Woods, 1999 (Box 11)
      - Autumn Ridge, 1999 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Pollution Prevention Report, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Schools-Pesticide Policy / Control, 1986-1991 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Solid Waste
      - Collection, 1996 (Box 11)
      - Education, 1994-2003 (Box 11)
      - Policy, 1987 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor (Southeast). Southeast Ann Arbor Natural Features Task Force, 1989-1994 (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor Wetlands Ordinance, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Auto Project, 1993-2004; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Bandemer Park Development Proposal, Undated (Box 11)
    - Bauman, Rob, 1997 (Box 11)
    - Block Coordinator Evaluation, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Block Coordinator Revamping, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Brownfield Redevelopment Authority, 2000 (Box 11)
    - CLEAN (Chlorine Elimination Action Network; formerly CONVERT), 1994-1995 (Box 11)
    - Clean Car Campaign, 2000-2004 (Box 11)
    - Clean Corporate Citizen, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Conservation Summit, 2001 (Box 11)
    - Dominos (proposed golf course), 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Don't Trash Michigan, 2000-2003; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Earth Day XX, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Earth Words (column in Chelsea and Dexter newspapers), 1990 (Box 11)
    - Ecology Center
      - Consumer's Guide to Lawn and Tree Care, 1989 (Box 11)
      - Press releases and other publicity, 1980s-2003 (Box 11)
      - Ecology Center as Regional Organization, 1996-2000 (Box 11)
    - Energy Works, 1990-1994 (Box 11)
    - Environmental Audit Privilege, 1995-1996 (Box 11)
    - Environmental Disposal Systems (EDS)
      - General, 1997-2003 (Box 12)
      - Romulus, 1993-1999 (Box 12)
    - Environmental Fund for Michigan (EFFM) / Earth Share of Michigan
      (In 2001 EFFM became Earth Share of Michigan)
      - General, 1992-1999; 6 folders (Box 12)
      - Financial, 1995-1999 (Box 12)
      - Strategic Planning Retreat, 1997 (Box 12)
      - United Way, 1994-2001 (Box 12)
      - Affiliation with Earth Share, 1996-2000 (Box 13)
      - Earth Share of Michigan, 2001-2003; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Environmental Issues Survey, 1992 (Box 13)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (regarding reorganization of Michigan's Department of Natural Resources), 1997 (Box 13)
    - Environmental Quality, Dept. of, Groundwater Rules, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Fight Back Fund, 1994 (Box 13)
    - Fish advisories and related, 1990s; 1 folders (Box 13)
    - Food Anti-Disparagement bill, 1996 (Box 13)
    - Fort Gratiot Landfill, undated (Box 13)
    - Fuller Oakway Woods, 1993 (Box 13)
    - GEE-WOW (Groundwater Education on Wheels), 1994-2004 (Box 13)
    - Gelman Sciences, 1989-1999; 5 folders (Box 13)
    - Golf courses and pesticides, 1986-1991 (Box 13)
    - Great Lakes Sustainable Organizations Project, 1994-1995 (Box 13)
    - Ground Up, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Holnam cement kilns (Dundee, Mich.) and toxic emissions, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Humbug Marsh (Detroit), 1999 (Box 13)
    - Issues Priority List, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Johnson Controls litigation, 1992-1996 (Box 13)
    - Kroger's organic produce, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Land Use / Transportation Project, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
    - Michigan Land Use Initiative, 1993-1996 (Box 13)
    - Michigan Pesticide Network, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Michigan Recycling Coalition, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Natural Resources Defense Council, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Natural Resources, Dept. of, recycling strategy, 1990-1994 (Box 14)
    - Neighborhood Action Network
      - General, 1998-2000 (Box 14)
      - Karl Steyaert file, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Newmarket Development, Pittsfield Township, 1998-1999 (Box 14)
    - North Main Street, Ann Arbor, 1986-1988 (Box 14)
    - Packaging and waste reduction ordinances, 1990-1991 (Box 14)
    - Pest Control Authority legislation, 1990-1991 (Box 14)
    - Pesticides